<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Dreamcatcher Blog</title>
        <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog</link>
        <description>Dreamcatcher Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JIT Application Delivery]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/11/04/JIT-applications</link>
            <guid>/2023/11/04/JIT-applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Delivering the Dreamcatcher: AI Assembled Applications Just In Time"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-11-04-jit-applications-ecb3e392976afedcd0087488afdf3d79.png" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><br><blockquote><p><strong>It isn't what you don't know that gets you, it's what you know for sure that just ain't so</strong></p><p><em>Software engineers when GPT4 passed the Turing Test</em></p></blockquote><p>Since 1950, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Turing Test</a> has been a benchmark in our efforts to develop intelligent machines. Recently, it has been surpassed, suggesting we might need to rethink our ideas about how we create and use computational technology.</p><p>In the past ten years, there has been an increase in the use of applications and what these applications can do. However, software construction efficiency has not advanced nearly as much. Our blockchain application framework was designed to make programming less complex, but it didn't address how to make communication between people building the software more efficient.</p><p>We are now shifting from a static to a dynamic application delivery model.</p><p>Here, AI assembles applications just in time, tailored to the user's instantaneous needs. Our blockchain makes programming less complex, so in some cases the AI can do that programming in real-time. By complete accident, the API for our blockchain is exactly the API OpenAI has chosen for letting GPT4 make API calls, meaning we can integrate AI seamlessly. In response, we have named our blockchain framework Artifact, as it is that which the AI leaves behind.</p><p>If a program is both delivered and coded in natural language, this reduces the distance between developers and users, letting users more directly engage with the system without the usual hindrance of the software industry.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="changes-to-the-application-delivery-model">Changes to the application delivery model<a class="hash-link" href="#changes-to-the-application-delivery-model" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Just-In-Time AI assembled applications - hereby refered to as 'Jitters' - are delivered through a single user interface, where user interaction is by natural language discourse with an AI assistant.
The single user interface is called Dreamcatcher, and the AI assistant is called HAL.</p><p>Jitter delivery differs from conventional delivery as follows:</p><p><strong>From applications to components</strong> A single user interface that continuously adapts allows users to tailor systems to their needs through composition, encouraging Jitter components to be modular and compatible.</p><p><strong>Real-time lifecycle</strong> Just-In-Time composition allows enhancements to Jitters to be enjoyed within seconds, instead of months, and to be integrated continously rather than via separate update processes and release cycles for each application</p><p><strong>Unification of Delivery</strong> Just-In-Time delivery removes the need for a conventional app store, as HAL scours for necessary components in real-time. A single billing arrangement can be made with the user, as well as a single authentication challenge, giving the user complete control of all data and AI interactions.</p><p><strong>Three Box UI</strong> The Dreamcatcher is presented with only three windows: chat input, chat history, and a stateboard. The dynamic AI controlled rendering of the stateboard ensures optimal data presentation, adapting in real-time to user interactions.</p><p>An example of this interface design taken from Palantir is shown here:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-11-04-palantir-chat-0fa039c2e9268df16c622e627fde3144.png" width="3129" height="1806" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>This is a breakdown of the essential elements of the interface:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-11-04-palantir-markup-191ae83dd22b7c7a32578789ab3f9a01.png" width="2217" height="1260" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>A video example of this interface design can be seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XEM5qz__HOU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> in use for the US military, which we found during a competitor search.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="contrast-to-the-software-industry">Contrast to the software industry<a class="hash-link" href="#contrast-to-the-software-industry" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Fred Brooks' seminal doctrine on software construction efficiency argues:</p><blockquote><p><strong>There is no single development, in either technology or in management technique, that by itself promises even one order-of-magnitude improvement in productivity, in reliability, in simplicity</strong></p><p><em>Fred Brooks - No Silver Bullet - 1986</em></p></blockquote><p>We challenge this notion in the post Turing Test world.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-old-way-months-long">The Old Way (months long)<a class="hash-link" href="#the-old-way-months-long" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-11-04-software-development-lifecycle-333203e9e04563092da52bddd2f52a63.png" width="815" height="345" class="img_ev3q">
This process would typically take weeks or months to cycle through and adapt to whatever changes had occured or been discovered since initiation, and the cost is typically high since human labour is required. The output is usually wrong in some way, and often not aimed at a single specific user request due to economic infeasibility.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="just-in-time-seconds-long">Just In Time (seconds long)<a class="hash-link" href="#just-in-time-seconds-long" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-11-04-agile-loop-9b32be1dce98bd44b8d70b4ab2ea3bf7.png" width="1545" height="980" class="img_ev3q">
In the Dreamcatcher, this whole cycle is managed by AI in very small chunks, at the instant the user wants something. Cycle time is measured in seconds, and cost is typically less than a cent per loop. However not every user request can be solved by HAL, and so when the system gets stuck on something, a broader innovation cycle is required involving a network of incentivized human innovation</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-innovation-network">The Innovation Network<a class="hash-link" href="#the-innovation-network" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Innovation Network within the Dreamcatcher is engaged whenever HAL gets stuck on something. It happens both silently in the background, or actively in conversation with the user about their needs. It works as follows:</p><ol><li><p><strong>A Stuck as the Unit of Innovation</strong>:
When HAL identifies that it is genuinely stuck in its service to the user, it creates an object out of it, named a "Stuck". These are NFTs on a public blockchain, and embody a problem within the Dreamcatcher. Stucks are valuable, as a high quality problem statement is the critical step in getting a high quality solution.</p></li><li><p><strong>Funding as incentivization</strong> Knowing that HAL has already vetted a Stuck as being unique, funding can be put against a Stuck to incentivize its solution, and HAL helps advertise the problem to those best suited to solve it.</p></li><li><p><strong>Integration within Jitters</strong>:
Once solved, HAL verifies the solution, the funds are dispersed, and the solution is immediately available to be incorporated into Jitters. Once it gathers traction within Jitter use, consumption payments start to flow to the contributors of the Stuck.</p></li><li><p><strong>Innovation becomes a Collective Endeavor</strong>:
The decentralized and AI integrated nature of the Innovation Network fosters a collective endeavor towards problem-solving. It makes users a collaborative part of continuous improvement, with an openness and connectedness that should outperform closed and disconnected innovation.</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="funding-pricing-and-revenue">Funding, Pricing, and Revenue<a class="hash-link" href="#funding-pricing-and-revenue" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The economic heart of this system is an AI powered, dynamic, ethical and fair machine that attributes to all who contribute. It sets the price paid for consumption, and says who receives the dispersal of each payment.</p><p>The transparency of blockchain enables trust, and the data processing power of AI allows it to consider all forms of contribution, which is a dataset too large for any human to parse effectively, and is a task too politically charged for any human to rule on without bias.</p><p>This is the Ambient Attribution System.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="funding-stucks">Funding Stucks<a class="hash-link" href="#funding-stucks" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The only type of funding in the system is escrow of funds against a Stuck to incentivize a solution. Once the Stuck is resolved, the funding is sent to the contributors, and the funding contribution is recognized in perpetuity. The contributions from the funders and solvers of Stucks form the sell side of the Stucks market.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pricing-model">Pricing Model:<a class="hash-link" href="#pricing-model" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Setting the price of consumption of Jitters is a difficult and delicate subject. The just in time nature prohibits a manual pricing model, and so the principles behind the automated version necessary for operation is provided:</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dynamic-pricing"><strong>Dynamic Pricing</strong>:<a class="hash-link" href="#dynamic-pricing" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>Setting the buy side price flexibly is crucial for fostering a fair environment conducive to maximal growth and economic throughput. The rewards received for a contribution change as more is learned about the true value that has been delivered.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ethical-and-fair-pricing"><strong>Ethical and Fair Pricing</strong>:<a class="hash-link" href="#ethical-and-fair-pricing" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>Ambient Attribution is calibrated to ensure ethical and fair pricing, functioning as a transparent and sensitive arbiter in determining pricing. Getting this right will result in maximal possible economic growth.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="revenue-streams">Revenue Streams:<a class="hash-link" href="#revenue-streams" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>In the Dreamcatcher, when financial transactions take place, Ambient Attribution clearly and traceably allocates the transaction's value among the resolved Stucks. This process turns resolved Stucks into an asset that can be traded, with its value based on future potential. There are three primary ways money can flow into the Dreamcatcher:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Computational Usage</strong>:
Dreamcatcher is an AI heavy application and requires fees to be able to run. We will start by marking up this charge, and attributing by way of Ambient Attribution to all the contributors that enabled the operation.</p></li><li><p><strong>Transaction fees upon Stuck Resolution</strong>:
When a Stuck is resolved, a portion of the dispersed funds will be due to the Dreamcatcher. These fees are expected to be around the 5% mark, depending on what the Ambient Attribution computes as a fair cut.</p></li><li><p><strong>HAL facilitated value exchange</strong>:
With HAL as a personal assistant, entities operating within the Dreamcatcher participate in deals brokered by AI, and employ Ambient Attriution to ensure pricing and attribution in those deals, in real-time. This seamless trading environment faintly looks like an Uberisation of everything.</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a class="hash-link" href="#conclusion" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Dreamcatcher, with its applications that adapt just in time, flexible pricing, and its network for fostering new ideas, blurs the line between users and developers, turning every interaction into a chance for tailor-made enhancements.</p><p>The flexible AI calculated pricing strategy promotes balanced growth with permissionless participation by providing fairness and clarity, making sure that everyone contributing is responsibly attributed to.</p><p>This approach turns every user into a prospective developer, with AI and blockchain technology facilitating immediate customization and new developments, while also ensuring fair payment for everyone's input. Here, applications are living, evolving entities, and problems therein are merely the starting points to further innovation.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dictionary">Dictionary<a class="hash-link" href="#dictionary" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>These are the terms introduced here:</p><p><strong>Jitters</strong> Applications assembled just in time by AI - brings the ability to deliver a feature a user asked for unforeseen by the developers, without any software release lifecycle</p><p><strong>Stucks</strong> Units of innovation - either open and needing to be done or resolved and usable in Jitters. Represented as NFTs and can be funded and traded. They are the target of attribution payments calculated by Ambient Attribution.</p><p><strong>Stuck NFT</strong> A Stuck that was considered important enough to expend gas on an ethereum compatible chain to turn it into an NFT which can be funded and traded.</p><p><strong>The Stucks Loop</strong> The innovation process where things that are stuck are turned into NFTs and worked on in a distributed fashion, and funded in a distributed way. Ambient Attribution disperses usage payments to the Stucks that the Jitter consumed to deliver value.</p><p><strong>Artifact</strong> The name for the blockchain framework we have developed that supports running AI enhanced blockchain objects with compute resources such as cpu, gpu, storage, networking, and consensus. It also provides side effect abilities to interface with external systems. It is the permanent memory left behind by the impermanent AI.</p><p><strong>HAL</strong> This is the name of the AI assistant that the Dreamcatcher presents as the primary means of intelligent interaction. All the resources of the Dreamcatcher are accessed via HAL.</p><p><strong>Pricing Model</strong> The price setting algorithm. A fair and transparent AI system that computes the price of any consumption or trade based on a personalized comprehensive analysis of the factors involved.</p><p><strong>Ambient Attribution</strong> The disperal of revenue algorithm. A fair and transparent AI system that allocates payments to contributors within the Innovation Network based on a comprehensive analysis of their involvement in generating the payment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Funding the Dreamcatcher]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/06/15/vc-funding</link>
            <guid>/2023/06/15/vc-funding</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Funding the Dreamcatcher: A Model for venture funding an AI powered Innovation network"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing" src="/assets/images/2023-06-15-vc-funding-07376fda567e2785b216eb146a36d955.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Dreamcatcher is an innovation network built on the confluence of blockchain, Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), and artificial intelligence (AI) to coordinate and incentivize contributors in a fair and transparent manner. The system brings together workers, investors, and existing technologies to expedite market solutions for customers, reducing time-to-market and enabling efficient utilization of global talent.  The AI is authoritative in determining attribution for contribution, and is made auditable by running natively on blockchain, avoiding hand crafted business models for each and every application, instead focusing on pure utility.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="components-and-functionality">Components and Functionality<a class="hash-link" href="#components-and-functionality" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Dreamcatcher system consists of three integral components:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Dreamcatcher Blockchain</strong>: A high compute capacity blockchain that operates on the principle of object-oriented programming with one blockchain per object. Each chain, capable of running on multiple computers, operates independently, enabling massive parallelism.  With this intense on-chain computation ability, blockchain native AI models can be run.  The blockchain ensures trust, transparency, and privacy, with data encryption at rest and in transit.</p></li><li><p><strong>Dreamcatcher Protocol</strong>: This protocol transforms work tasks into NFTs, decentralizing the work management model and making it accessible to the global talent pool. The protocol initiates with the definition of a task (referred to as a Packet), followed by independent QA review. Once approved, the Packet opens for funding, with the proceeds held in escrow until a suitable solution is proposed and approved.  These NFTs are available for trade on OpenSea and other marketplaces as shown in the adjacent figure.</p></li></ol><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-06-13-opensea-nft-listing-38522b9032ec2754850efc39c007921b.png" width="2198" height="2196" class="img_ev3q"></p><ol start="3"><li><strong>Dreamcatcher AI</strong>: Trained on the protocol dataset and running natively on the blockchain, the Dreamcatcher AI fairly attributes to contributions based on interactions recorded in the NFTs. Continuous protocol data further adjusts and refines the decentralized AI's decisions, ensuring consistent and accurate contribution tracking, even as societal awareness of fairness evolves.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="value-proposition">Value Proposition<a class="hash-link" href="#value-proposition" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Dreamcatcher inverts the work-value interaction by externalizing tasks into discrete, competitive NFTs, labeled "Packets". This decentralized model emphasizes productivity, tying compensation directly to useful results. Packets, organized akin to a gantt chart, offer management direct control over budget and timelines. </p><p>Dreamcatcher's AI serves as the default business model, attributing payments to contributors based on NFT-recorded contributions. This obviates the need for costly and often flawed self-devised business models, focusing on maximal customer utility instead. The AI also projects future NFT worth, incentivizing continual software maintenance.</p><p>Publicly available NFTs enable task identification and combination across organizations, maximizing funding and royalties while expediting project completion. Furthermore, Dreamcatcher expands funding opportunities, promoting a globally participative and innovative workforce, contrasting with traditional, insular internal company funding.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="future-development-and-funding">Future Development and Funding<a class="hash-link" href="#future-development-and-funding" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Dreamcatcher's challenges involve the AI development for fair attribution, the blockchain extension to handle this new workload, but most of all scalable network growth of participants.  Starting a public company to raise additional funding will boost talent acquisition via increased packet funding, enhance publicity, and establish legitimacy. The stock offers an investment opportunity for those preferring financial contribution over active task involvement. As the public company accrues balance sheet income from the Dreamcatcher and reports NFTs as assets, analysts can predict future company stock value, promising favorable returns for investors.  Our initial partnerships will be focused around Satoshi Island - a blockchain native smart city initiative, as the success of members is the most important aspect of the Dreamcatcher’s success.</p><p>Much like the Internet, the Dreamcatcher's full impact is largely unpredictable, with its usage and evolution firmly in the hands of its global community - it will be defined more by what gets done with it than how it was built.  We hope it will appear over time as though the Internet finally developed a brain, with the humans supplying novelty, and the Dreamcatcher AI ensuring a fair and cooperative environment for them to rapidly collaborate in real time with near zero friction commerce.</p><p>If we can get the most basic version of the Dreamcatcher operating with the elements described herein, the long term result should be a displacement of other blockchains, as the winner in any environment is that which can evolve.  The Dreamcatcher is built as though it was evolution itself, endlessly reinforcing its valuable parts, discarding that which it no longer needs.  These evolutionary forces are external in other blockchain ecosystems, and give them a fatal weakness.  Should the Dreamcatcher manage to take hold in the far-from-over blockchain race and additionally in the just-getting-started AI race, the perpetual royalties fairly due to the early contributor NFTs ought to be significant.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tasks as NFTs]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/06/13/tasks-as-NFTs</link>
            <guid>/2023/06/13/tasks-as-NFTs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Transforming Tasks into NFTs: When Events become Things in the Packet-Based Innovation System"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: a gantt chart with a simple collection of tasks and dependencies in a waterfall arrangment, but what is special is that each task has attached to it a unique image which is an NFT" src="/assets/images/2023-06-13-NFTs-as-tasks-8bd07eb90166ba5b534c625a516be5fe.png" width="1510" height="1458" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In an increasingly interconnected world, innovation often emerges from unexpected intersections. In the pervasive interconnectedness of the digital world, the Dreamcatcher platform introduces a novel approach to task management. By leveraging the capabilities of Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), the Dreamcatcher introduces a system where tasks are transformed into NFTs that are termed 'Packets'. This conversion allows tasks, now manifested as Packets, to obtain an existence characterized by tangibility, tradability, and transparency. The core principle behind this transformation is reminiscent of packet-switched networks, wherein data is segmented into distinct packets that are independently routed.</p><p>Dreamcatcher's platform decentralizes and breaks down ideas or innovations into smaller parts, facilitating their independent evolution. This concept draws a parallel with Uber's packet-switched labor model, which paves the way for a flexible workforce. Dreamcatcher expands this idea to the domain of innovation, where Packets, representing tasks as NFTs, emerge as dynamic entities. These entities fuel collective innovation, diverging from the traditional model where a single organization or entity dictates the progress. Despite the inherent challenges, this model shapes a resilient and adaptive innovation network, one that readily embraces discontinuity and transformation processes.</p><p>In its initial iteration, the Dreamcatcher platform, built on the Ethereum blockchain, utilizes a smart contract to hold funds in escrow. This provides workers with the confidence that they will receive payment for their contributions and offers collaborative funders a clear view of the contributions made by each participant. Additionally, these Packets can be freely traded on platforms like OpenSea, enriching the market's depth.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Example Listing on Opensea the worlds largest NFT marketplace" src="/assets/images/2023-06-13-opensea-nft-listing-38522b9032ec2754850efc39c007921b.png" width="2198" height="2196" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Harnessing the power of blockchain, Dreamcatcher establishes a direct link between economic rewards and the value of members' contributions. This technology guarantees the integrity and ownership of these Packets, each representing a single unit of software or documented knowledge. The Packets can be exchanged based on their anticipated future value, serving both as a record of contribution and a target for attribution, thereby incentivizing innovation.</p><p>The platform also offers a mechanism for identifying and merging duplicate Packets, thereby promoting resource sharing and efficiency. By symbolizing tasks as NFTs or Packets, Dreamcatcher facilitates the generation of auto-updating project roadmaps that can be disseminated across separate companies.</p><p>In summary, Dreamcatcher's approach fosters transparency and efficiency in innovation networks. By translating tasks into Packets, it gives rise to a dynamic, resilient, and adaptive network that directly correlates value with individual contributions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unfolding the Dreamcatcher]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/06/13/unfolding-the-dreamcatcher</link>
            <guid>/2023/06/13/unfolding-the-dreamcatcher</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Unfolding the Dreamcatcher: The Confluence of Blockchain, AI, and NFTs in a New Era of Innovation Networks"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: create an image depicting the confluence of blockchain, AI, and NFTs to create an equitable innovation network. Make it look futuristic and somehow trigger the notion of a dreamcatcher." src="/assets/images/2023-06-13-unfolding-the-dreamcatcher-7d715d6e5064b32c71b38f3dcfad8a6a.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>When it comes to technological innovation, the path forward is rarely a straight line. The journey is often filled with trials and tribulations, twists and turns, and a series of highs and lows. One such journey is the development of the Dreamcatcher, an innovative solution that combined the prowess of blockchain technology, the intellect of artificial intelligence (AI), and the uniqueness of non-fungible tokens (NFTs) to create a self-reinforcing innovation network. This blog post recounts the intricate journey that led to the Dreamcatcher's creation and explores its revolutionary potential. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="from-blockchain-to-innovation-networks">From Blockchain to Innovation Networks<a class="hash-link" href="#from-blockchain-to-innovation-networks" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>At the outset, the journey began with a high compute ability blockchain, which allowed for the creation of private chains and applications composed of many such chains. The potential of this technology was evident, yet a significant hurdle remained - charging for its use was a conundrum yet to be resolved. </p><p>This uncertainty triggered internal pressures within the team. The question of how to adequately compensate our staff and external contributors for a valuable, yet uncertain asset - the blockchain - was a divisive issue.  We knew the primary value for us to unlock was an ecosystem - how could we capture a fair share of the value the applications generated, without smothering growth ? Simultaneously, we were grappling with another monumental challenge: how to leverage the blockchain to create a global innovation network - how could we have no staff whatsoever, and join the partners we wanted to enable in the ecosystem as participants ? The question was:</p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-danger alert alert--danger admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M5.05.31c.81 2.17.41 3.38-.52 4.31C3.55 5.67 1.98 6.45.9 7.98c-1.45 2.05-1.7 6.53 3.53 7.7-2.2-1.16-2.67-4.52-.3-6.61-.61 2.03.53 3.33 1.94 2.86 1.39-.47 2.3.53 2.27 1.67-.02.78-.31 1.44-1.13 1.81 3.42-.59 4.78-3.42 4.78-5.56 0-2.84-2.53-3.22-1.25-5.61-1.52.13-2.03 1.13-1.89 2.75.09 1.08-1.02 1.8-1.86 1.33-.67-.41-.66-1.19-.06-1.78C8.18 5.31 8.68 2.45 5.05.32L5.03.3l.02.01z"></path></svg></span><mdxadmonitiontitle>&nbsp;<!-- --> </mdxadmonitiontitle></div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p><strong>How could the platform be a peer of the applications ? </strong></p></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-advent-of-the-dreamcatcher">The Advent of the Dreamcatcher<a class="hash-link" href="#the-advent-of-the-dreamcatcher" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>In the midst of these challenges, we conceptualized the first rendition of the Dreamcatcher. It was a tangible entity that functioned as a board game and a paper version. This Dreamcatcher was our first stepping stone in the path toward a more comprehensive solution.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Dreamcatcher as a board game" src="/assets/images/2023-06-13-boardgame-dreamcatcher-9681ccded1660e7e707aed5fe8605244.jpg" width="4032" height="1960" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We carried on experimenting on paper and in text documents to try to get the protocol right, but it seemed increasingly difficult to make a simple model stick together in complex environments.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-intersection-of-nfts-and-task-attribution">The Intersection of NFTs and Task Attribution<a class="hash-link" href="#the-intersection-of-nfts-and-task-attribution" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Then NFTs blew up on the scene, and quickly grew to demonstrate multiple billions of dollars in yearly transactions.</p><p>The next breakthrough for the Dreamcatcher came when we realized, through the experience of <a href="https://satoshi-island.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Satoshi Island</a>, where they had turned NFTs into land, that tasks could be turned into NFTs. This realization opened up a world of possibilities for task attribution and compensation.</p><p>This provided a way to make a simple protocol based on the ERC-1155 token standard, that could apply to a large number of complex use cases.  No sooner had this model been contained when along came ChatGPT...</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enter-ai">Enter AI<a class="hash-link" href="#enter-ai" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Suddenly we looked at the large compute capacity blockchain we had been working on, and saw it could be quite simply utlized to run AI models.  A blockchain native AI had its uses for sure, but we caught a glimpse of something more fundamental - fairness.</p><p>The greatest innovation network possible is one that is the fairest to all participants.  Our goal was to ensure fairness of reward for all participants and we now had a protocol that could generate a dataset about that very thing in a nice compact and standard form.  Most importantly, this dataset was immutable.</p><p>This means we can use the NFT task protocol as a dataset to train a blockchain-native AI that would provide instant and unbiased attribution based on the contribution patterns left by protocol usage.  </p><p>Think about that a second:  </p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-tip alert alert--success admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M6.5 0C3.48 0 1 2.19 1 5c0 .92.55 2.25 1 3 1.34 2.25 1.78 2.78 2 4v1h5v-1c.22-1.22.66-1.75 2-4 .45-.75 1-2.08 1-3 0-2.81-2.48-5-5.5-5zm3.64 7.48c-.25.44-.47.8-.67 1.11-.86 1.41-1.25 2.06-1.45 3.23-.02.05-.02.11-.02.17H5c0-.06 0-.13-.02-.17-.2-1.17-.59-1.83-1.45-3.23-.2-.31-.42-.67-.67-1.11C2.44 6.78 2 5.65 2 5c0-2.2 2.02-4 4.5-4 1.22 0 2.36.42 3.22 1.19C10.55 2.94 11 3.94 11 5c0 .66-.44 1.78-.86 2.48zM4 14h5c-.23 1.14-1.3 2-2.5 2s-2.27-.86-2.5-2z"></path></svg></span><mdxadmonitiontitle>&nbsp;<!-- --> </mdxadmonitiontitle></div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p><strong>Instant unbiased fair reward for your permissionless labor and investment, in perpetuity</strong></p></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-dreamcatcher-today-a-self-reinforcing-innovation-network">The Dreamcatcher Today: A Self-Reinforcing Innovation Network<a class="hash-link" href="#the-dreamcatcher-today-a-self-reinforcing-innovation-network" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Today, we believe we have something extremely valuable in the Dreamcatcher. It can charge and reward anyone participating in the Dreamcatcher blockchain using the Dreamcatcher Protocol. This protocol immutably requests and records contributions for anything at all.</p><p>Though it might be possible to attempt fairness for tasks outside the Dreamcatcher protocol, our initial scope is limited to protocol activity as we build up.  One of the traits we knew a suitable Dreamcatcher design would possess is the ability to create and continually improve its own self, and so using this system, we are building this system and all the apps on top of it. </p><p>The Dreamcatcher journey is a testament to the unpredictability and excitement of technological innovation. It underscores how technologies, when brought together, can create something truly unique and powerful. The fusion of blockchain, AI, and NFTs has not only resolved our initial challenges but also opened up new avenues for equitable innovation and collaboration.</p><p>As we continue on this journey, we remain steadfast in our commitment to foster a fair and robust innovation network. Through the Dreamcatcher, we hope to democratize the innovation process, providing every participant with the recognition and reward they deserve.</p><p>Here's to the journey ahead, and the many more exciting chapters to be added to the story of the Dreamcatcher, where the highlight must surely be what the Dreamcatcher has made.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI and the Wealth of Nations]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/24/ai-and-the-wealth-of-nations</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/24/ai-and-the-wealth-of-nations</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"A Comprehensive Evaluation of Artificial Intelligence and its Implications for Adam Smith's Economic Theories in The Wealth of Nations"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image showing ai impacting the wealth of nations like a lightbulb comet smashing into the world" src="/assets/images/2023-05-24-ai-wealth-of-nations-be2e274194767045f510ad42d44c620a.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="abstract">Abstract:<a class="hash-link" href="#abstract" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>This paper explores the potential impact and intersection of artificial intelligence (AI) with the economic principles put forward by Adam Smith in "The Wealth of Nations". While some scholars argue that AI will radically disrupt conventional economic frameworks, including division of labor, market competition, and the metaphorical "invisible hand", counter-arguments posit that AI might not significantly alter these frameworks or could even strengthen them. This paper investigates these diverse viewpoints, shedding light on the ongoing discourse about the future economic implications of AI.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction:<a class="hash-link" href="#introduction" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Adam Smith's magnum opus, "The Wealth of Nations," has long served as a cornerstone of modern economic theory. Its key concepts have guided economic policy and thought since its publication in 1776. However, the rapid advancement and adoption of artificial intelligence (AI) raises questions about the continuing relevance of these theories. This paper endeavors to scrutinize the potential ramifications of AI on Smith's core economic principles and presents counter-arguments to some commonly held assumptions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="section-1-understanding-adam-smiths-the-wealth-of-nations">Section 1: Understanding Adam Smith's "The Wealth of Nations"<a class="hash-link" href="#section-1-understanding-adam-smiths-the-wealth-of-nations" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>"The Wealth of Nations" has long served as a seminal text for economic thought, pioneering the basic principles that form the foundation of capitalist economies. Its pervasive influence and enduring relevance cannot be overstated, especially when juxtaposed with the rapid technological advances of our era, particularly artificial intelligence (AI). In this field, it's not unreasable to ask whether these core principles may change, shaping and possibly redefining economic systems and societal structures.</p><p>At the heart of "The Wealth of Nations" is Smith's theory of labor division, which promotes the concept of job specialization. He observed that when labor is divided among workers, allowing each to specialize in a specific task, efficiency and productivity are significantly enhanced. This is primarily because workers can develop a high level of proficiency in their respective tasks, leading to increased output and lower costs. This argument was groundbreaking at the time, proposing a shift from a Jack-of-all-trades approach to a more focused, specialized form of labor. Today, this principle forms the foundation of modern industry and services, where tasks are divided among various departments and individuals, each specializing in a unique area.</p><p>Additionally, Smith's advocacy for free markets argued that they operate most efficiently when left to the forces of supply and demand, with limited intervention from the government. This was in stark contradication to Merchantalism, the prelevant theory of the day which can be summarised as a "zero-sum game", where trade takes from one and gives to another.  </p><p>Smith argued that competition and self-interest drive economic activity, leading to innovation, lower prices, and improved quality of goods and services. Although mentioned only once by Smith, the phrase "invisible hand" serves to demonstrate the point; self-regulating market dynamics ensures that resources are allocated most efficiently to meet society's needs without the need for centralised control or tarrifs.  </p><p>This "invisible hand" metaphor embodies Smith's belief in the natural equilibrium of markets. He postulated that if every individual were allowed to pursue their self-interest, markets would naturally gravitate towards an equilibrium where supply meets demand, thereby promoting general economic prosperity. This perspective resonates in many of today's economies, where free-market principles often guide policy-making and business strategy.</p><p>However, the rise of artificial intelligence challenges us to reexamine these principles. With AI's capabilities to perform a range of tasks, from data analysis to pattern recognition and even creative tasks, there are questions about its potential impact on the division of labor. Could AI lead to a new form of labor division where machines handle not only repetitive tasks but also cognitive tasks that were traditionally the domain of humans? Could this lead to greater efficiency and productivity, or could it displace workers and widen economic disparities?</p><p>Similarly, what would be the implications of AI on market dynamics? Could AI disrupt market competition by favoring companies that can afford to invest in this technology, thereby challenging the balance that the "invisible hand" is supposed to maintain? Or could AI foster a new wave of innovation, driving competition and efficiency in ways that further underscore the principles advocated by Smith?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="section-2-ais-influence-on-smiths-division-of-labor">Section 2: AI’s Influence on Smith's Division of Labor<a class="hash-link" href="#section-2-ais-influence-on-smiths-division-of-labor" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The fear of machines replacing human labor is not a new phenomenon. Each industrial revolution has brought with it a wave of technological advancements, and with these advancements have come fears of widespread unemployment. In the context of AI, these fears are compounded by the technology's unprecedented capabilities. Unlike previous technologies, AI can perform cognitive tasks that were previously thought to be the exclusive domain of humans. This includes tasks such as analyzing large datasets to identify trends, making complex calculations, understanding and providing legal documents, and even creating music and art. As such, the potential for AI to replace human labor extends beyond manual jobs to include white-collar jobs as well.</p><p>Despite these valid concerns, there is another side to this argument that deserves careful consideration. Historically, technological advancements have led to changes in labor markets, but these changes have not necessarily resulted in net job losses. Rather, they have led to the evolution of labor markets, with new industries and job roles emerging to replace those that become obsolete.</p><p>Consider the Industrial Revolution. The mechanization of production led to the widespread displacement of artisans and craftsmen, leading many to fear a future of rampant unemployment. However, as history shows, these fears were largely unfounded. The Industrial Revolution did not result in mass unemployment. Instead, it created new industries and job roles that had not existed before. Workers were required to acquire new skills to operate and maintain the newly invented machinery, leading to an increase in overall employment.</p><p>Similarly, the advent of computers and the internet led to significant shifts in labor markets. Many jobs were automated, and certain industries became obsolete. However, the same technological advancements also led to the creation of entirely new sectors like software development, digital marketing, cybersecurity, and more. Furthermore, they increased productivity and efficiency in existing industries, leading to economic growth.</p><p>These historical precedents serve as compelling counter-arguments to the notion that AI will result in significant job losses. It is plausible, and indeed likely, that AI will drive the creation of new industries and job roles. For instance, there is already growing demand for AI specialists who can develop and maintain AI systems, and specialists who can use those systems to best effect. Furthermore, as AI systems become more integrated into our economy, there will be increased demand for roles that complement these systems. This includes jobs that require complex decision-making, emotional intelligence, creativity, and interpersonal skills – attributes that are inherently human and challenging for AI to replicate.</p><p>Moreover, AI has the potential to augment human labor, thereby increasing productivity and economic growth. AI can automate mundane and repetitive tasks, freeing up workers to focus on tasks that add more value. For instance, AI could automate data entry and analysis, allowing human workers to focus on interpreting the results and making strategic decisions. In the healthcare sector for example, AI could automate routine diagnoses and administrative tasks, allowing doctors to spend more time interacting with patients and addressing complex medical issues.</p><p>While the advent of AI is likely to disrupt traditional labor markets, history suggests that this disruption may lead to the evolution of labor markets rather than their downfall. As with previous technological advancements, the key to navigating this transition will likely involve education and reskilling, ensuring that workers are equipped with the skills needed to thrive in an increasingly AI-driven economy.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="section-3-ais-impact-on-market-competition-and-the-invisible-hand">Section 3: AI's Impact on Market Competition and the Invisible Hand<a class="hash-link" href="#section-3-ais-impact-on-market-competition-and-the-invisible-hand" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>AI's Impact on Market Competition and the Invisible Hand</p><p>With AI's impressive capabilities to increase efficiency and reduce costs, it holds substantial implications for competition and market equilibrium, potentially reshaping the landscape of free markets, typically understand as Smith's "Invisible Hand".</p><p>AI’s potential impact on market competition is multifold. At one end of the spectrum, AI is viewed as a significant driver of efficiency and productivity, capable of fostering intense competition. By automating tasks, optimizing processes, and generating valuable insights from vast amounts of data, AI can drastically reduce costs and improve the quality of goods and services. This enhanced efficiency could spur competition, driving companies to innovate continually to stay ahead. It may favor new modes of working, and collaboration.  Theoretically, the outcome could be lower prices, improved product quality, and greater variety, echoing Smith's proposition that competition catalyzes economic prosperity.</p><p>However, the optimism surrounding AI's capacity to boost competition is tempered by concerns about potential market imbalances. AI development and deployment demand significant investment, including high-quality data, sophisticated hardware, and skilled personnel. Consequently, larger corporations with ample resources are better positioned to harness AI's benefits, risking an asymmetrical distribution of market power both economically and geographically.  AI risks  monopolies or oligopolies forming, stifling competition and potentially inhibiting innovation.</p><p>Despite this concern, it is essential to recognize the inherent dynamism of free markets, which might serve as a counterweight to this potential imbalance. Driven by the pressure of competition and the lure of profit, market forces could propel the development of cost-effective AI solutions. Smaller companies and startups, despite their limited resources, have frequently been the harbingers of disruptive innovations. Leveraging their agility and creativity, they could devise affordable AI solutions that level the playing field, preserving, and potentially even enhancing, market competition.</p><p>The influence of AI therefore potentially extends the notion of the "invisible hand", with individual self-interest and competition naturally guiding the economy towards equilibrium. The advent of AI, with its capacity to make optimized decisions, poses intriguing questions about this concept of market equilibrium.</p><p>However, a valid concern may arise from AI's ability to optimize for specific outcomes, potentially outperforming and outpacing human decision-making. AI's predictive capabilities, combined with its capacity to process vast amounts of data, could theoretically lead to market efficiencies that far exceed those possible with human decision-making alone. This unprecedented efficiency could disrupt the natural equilibrium of markets, leading for example to feedback loops in markets based solely on competition between similar learning sets and the potential negative spiral that may result.  It would therefore be wise to employ safeguards whenever AI is used to automate processes with other AI in an unbounded state.</p><p>Counter-arguments suggest that AI, as a tool designed and operated by humans, inherently reflects human objectives. Consequently, it would not disrupt market equilibrium unless explicitly programmed to do so. AI's influence would be subject to the strategic goals and ethical considerations of its human operators. In essence, AI would merely be an extension of human decision-making, enabling more accurate and efficient decisions but still operating within the broader framework of human-guided market dynamics.</p><p>Clearly, until the relative weight of these arguments are more fully understood, and their potential impact on markets of all sorts can be guaged, caution would be advised.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="section-4-relevance-of-smiths-theories-in-an-ai-driven-future">Section 4: Relevance of Smith's Theories in an AI-Driven Future<a class="hash-link" href="#section-4-relevance-of-smiths-theories-in-an-ai-driven-future" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>It is undeniable that AI introduces novel dynamics into the economic landscape, sparking debates about the viability of longstanding economic principles. </p><p>Smith's principles, namely labor division, self-interest, competition, and the operation of supply and demand, have already endured through various industrial revolutions and technological disruptions. The current rise of AI and its implications for these principles may be similar.  That, however, is not certain.</p><p>Take the division of labor.  With AI's ability to automate tasks and potentially specialize in certain areas previously dominated by humans, this principle takes on new dimensions. However, the essence of Smith's argument remains valid; specialization, be it human or machine, contributes to efficiency. The introduction of AI simply expands the scope of specialization to include not just human labor, but also machine intelligence.  It need not change the nature and impact of specialization.</p><p>Moreover, Smith's concept of self-interest as a driving force in economic activity remains as relevant as ever. In the context of AI, self-interest could be viewed as the motivation behind the adoption and development of AI technologies. Businesses, in their quest for profitability and competitive advantage, will invest in AI if it improves efficiency, enhances customer service, or creates innovative products and services. Individuals, seeking personal convenience and improved quality of life, are likely to increase their use of AI-enabled devices and services. Thus, the pursuit of self-interest, as Smith outlined, continues to fuel economic activity and technological advancement.</p><p>Similarly, competition. Companies may compete fiercely in the development and application of AI, striving to outperform rivals by offering superior, AI-enhanced products and services, but nevertheless this is competition which, as Smith pointed out, ultimately benefits all. Moreover, as previously discussed, this competition could spur innovation in cost-effective AI solutions, particularly from smaller businesses and startups, ensuring that market competition remains vibrant.</p><p>The operation of supply and demand, another fundamental principle posited by Smith, also remains intact in the face of AI. Demand for AI technologies is influenced by factors such as perceived benefits, affordability, and societal acceptance. In turn, the supply of AI technologies is determined by research progress, regulatory environments, and economic viability. Here, the "invisible hand" continues its work, guiding the AI market towards an equilibrium where supply meets demand.</p><p>Thus, counter-arguments propose that the rise of AI, while certainly transformative, does not necessitate the construction of entirely new economic models. Instead, we may find it more useful to adapt existing models, those that have stood the test of time and proven their resilience to technological disruptions, to account for the influences of AI.  Proposals such as a Universal Income to help transition between the 'now' economy and the 'next' may well be needed to reduce societal push-back.</p><p>This perspective advocates for a continuity of economic thought, even in the face of disruptive change. Smith's theories, deeply embedded in our economic systems, are unlikely to be nullified by AI. Instead, these fundamental forces will continue to shape the development, deployment, and use of AI technology, just as they have with past technological advancements.</p><p>While the advent of AI undoubtedly poses significant challenges and uncertainties, it also presents an opportunity to reexamine and reaffirm the enduring relevance of Smith's principles. It is likely to be make irrelevant many professions previously considered necessary; it is equally likely to democratise opportunity by removing those necessities.  As we navigate this AI-driven era, we will continue to grapple with, adapt, and apply these principles, ensuring that our economic systems remain robust, dynamic, and resilient.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion:<a class="hash-link" href="#conclusion" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Adam Smith's "The Wealth of Nations" provides us with an enduring framework for understanding the dynamics of labor and markets within market-led economies. Smith's principles of labor division and market self-regulation, embodied by his metaphor of the "invisible hand", remain highly relevant today. However, with the advent of artificial intelligence, we are challenged to reevaluate and potentially redefine these fundamental principles.</p><p>AI's capacity to perform both repetitive and cognitive tasks calls for a careful reassessment of Smith's division of labor theory. While fears of AI leading to widespread job losses are not unfounded, historical precedents suggest that technology-induced job displacement often paves the way for new industries and roles. It is anticipated that AI will drive a similar evolution in labor markets, creating demand for new skills and roles, and possibly augmenting human labor to increase productivity and economic growth.</p><p>The impact of AI on market dynamics is another area of critical interest. On one hand, AI could potentially disrupt market competition and challenge the balance that Smith's "invisible hand" maintains. On the other hand, AI might also foster innovation and efficiency in ways that further enhance the principles espoused by Smith.</p><p>Thus, as we navigate this AI-driven era, engaging with Smith's foundational economic principles becomes essential. While the interaction of AI with these principles poses significant questions and challenges, it also opens up opportunities for insightful dialogue and exploration. How these principles adapt and evolve to accommodate AI's transformative capabilities will be central to shaping our economic systems and societal structures in the coming years.</p><p>Ultimately, as we stride forward into the era of artificial intelligence, it is crucial to remember the enduring relevance of Smith's work. We should continually reassess and reinterpret these theories, embrace new methods and frameworks, deemphasise static truths; the future is likely to be led by dynamic frameworks, hopefully cushioned by suitable safeguards for individuals and society alike, but which can adapt significantly faster to the changing contours of technology and society. This will not only help us mitigate potential risks but also harness the transformative potential of AI to create more prosperous and equitable economic systems.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Primal Needs: Attribution for Contribution]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/23/Primal-Needs-Attribution-for-Contribution</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/23/Primal-Needs-Attribution-for-Contribution</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Restoring Fair Reward: Dreamcatcher's Packet-Based Innovation Rekindles the Ancient Link between Contribution and Attribution"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image representing the ancient primal link between contribution and attribution, work and reward" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-primal-needs-f3dfdd015df67e0fcfcc6be70fa5d276.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>From the earliest days of humanity, the drive to contribute and to be fairly rewarded for our effort has been a fundamental part of our nature. This primal, animalistic desire for fair attribution has influenced the formation of societies, economies, and even our individual identities. Yet, in our current economic system, it appears that the link between contribution and reward, between effort and income, has become increasingly tenuous. The flow of wealth from its source to those who contribute to its creation seems distorted and, in some cases, corrupted. This raises the question: how can we restore this essential link? The answer may lie in an innovative approach – packet-based innovation.</p><p>Dreamcatcher, an open, packetized innovation market, offers a groundbreaking solution to this problem. By employing a packet-based innovation model, it reinstates the direct connection between economic reward and the value of members' contributions. In this system, members deal in 'Packets' - unitary pieces of software or documented knowledge whose quality has been verified by a trusted, disinterested Quality Assurance (QA) process, and which address an identified need.</p><p>In essence, each packet represents a quantifiable unit of contribution. The QA process ensures that each packet meets a certain standard of quality, removing ambiguity and ensuring that all contributions are assessed fairly. This system allows Dreamcatcher to connect economic rewards directly to the value of a member's contribution, reinforcing the link between effort and income that seems to have drifted in the traditional capitalistic model.</p><p>Furthermore, Dreamcatcher's model also ensures fair attribution. Once a packet is deemed 'done', it acts like immutable equity that cannot be diluted or taken away. It is owned by all members who contributed to its creation. This innovative approach ensures that those who contribute are fairly and directly rewarded for their efforts, reinforcing the connection between contribution and attribution.</p><p>Moreover, the ability to reuse and recombine packets in multiple applications allows for the creation of passive income streams for the original contributors, further strengthening the link between effort and reward. </p><p>In Dreamcatcher's packet-based innovation market, all members, including funders, do-ers, and buyers, have an equal opportunity to contribute and receive fair reward for their efforts. The QA process ensures that the work done meets the required standards and that the funds are used effectively. Do-ers are rewarded based solely on the quality of their work, and buyers, by virtue of their demand for a product, share in the rewards when the product is built and used.</p><p>In conclusion, packet-based innovation presents a promising avenue for restoring the ancient, primal link between contribution and attribution. By breaking down innovation into quantifiable, quality-assured packets, Dreamcatcher's model ensures that every contribution is fairly rewarded, effectively addressing the distortions and corruptions seen in the traditional flow of wealth. By restoring this essential link, packet-based innovation offers not only a more equitable approach to economic reward, but also a more inclusive and sustainable model for the future of innovation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dawn of Inverted Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/23/inverted-apps-dawn</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/23/inverted-apps-dawn</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Revolutionizing the Digital Landscape: Inverted Apps, Championing Consumer-Centric Operation"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image of a application that has been inverted to serve its consumers rather than its controllers, in the form a swarm of robotic production lines with a colorful starburst as its backdrop" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-inverted-apps-dawn-1f92da589c5d92a6f99910260a7420fb.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The digital world is continually evolving, and one of the latest advancements is the rise of inverted applications, or "inverted apps." Rooted in the principles of decentralization, these apps are pioneering a new approach to application operation and development, putting consumers first and redefining the notion of control.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-are-inverted-apps">What are Inverted Apps?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-are-inverted-apps" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Inverted apps are a unique breed of digital applications that put their consumers at the forefront. Instead of following a central authority or rigid structural framework, they coordinate organically while being fractured into many pieces. This decentralization allows them to tailor their operations around the needs and desires of their users, not just their controllers or developers.</p><p>The magic behind this consumer-centric operation is facilitated by the Dreamcatcher platform, which provides the tools and infrastructure for inverted capital allocation mechanisms. These mechanisms allow resources to be distributed in ways that maximize user benefit, leading to a more user-friendly and engaging digital experience.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-power-of-decentralization">The Power of Decentralization<a class="hash-link" href="#the-power-of-decentralization" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The beauty of inverted apps lies in their decentralized structure. Unlike traditional decentralized apps, which often still harbor some form of central control—be it a token or a central registry of intent—inverted apps operate without any central coordination. </p><p>This lack of central authority does not mean that inverted apps are chaotic or disorganized. Instead, any central tendencies that do emerge do so naturally and become apparent only when entities communicate. This fluid and flexible structure allows inverted apps to adapt and evolve in response to user feedback, promoting a more organic and user-centered development process.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-consumer-centric-operation-matters">Why Consumer-Centric Operation Matters<a class="hash-link" href="#why-consumer-centric-operation-matters" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The consumer-centric operation of inverted apps is not just a novel idea—it's a game-changer. For far too long, digital applications have been designed and developed with a top-down approach, with developers or corporations dictating the terms of use and control.</p><p>Inverted apps break away from this paradigm, instead putting the power in the hands of the users. This approach fosters a more engaging and satisfying user experience, as users feel heard and valued, and the apps themselves become more responsive and adaptable.</p><p>The ability of inverted apps to coordinate while being fractured into many pieces also presents several advantages. It allows for a high degree of customization and personalization, as different pieces of the app can adapt to different user needs. Moreover, it increases resilience, as the failure or compromise of one piece does not affect the functionality of the whole.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-future-of-inverted-apps">The Future of Inverted Apps<a class="hash-link" href="#the-future-of-inverted-apps" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The advent of inverted apps marks a significant shift in the digital landscape, one that prioritizes user needs and experiences above all else. As more and more developers embrace this consumer-centric approach, we can expect to see a new generation of digital applications that are more responsive, adaptable, and engaging than ever before.</p><p>While the journey of inverted apps is just beginning, their potential is vast. They represent a powerful testament to the power of decentralization and the importance of putting consumers first. As they continue to evolve and mature, inverted apps are set to redefine our digital experiences, ushering in a new era of consumer-centric operation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Only Two Attribution Decisions]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/23/the-only-two-attribution-decisions</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/23/the-only-two-attribution-decisions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"The Art and Science of Fair Attribution: Apportioning Rewards in the Dreamcatcher Ecosystem"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image showing the only two kinds of attribution decision required in the dreamcatcher: contribution vs contribution, and funding vs contribution vs prior art" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-two-attribution-types-621e88e29639c9b7c8097cb2f157d8cf.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In the Dreamcatcher ecosystem, the value of everyone's contributions is recognized and rewarded, thanks to a unique model of attribution. But how does one decide what counts as a "contribution"? And what's more, how does one determine the relative weight of different kinds of contributions? In this post, we'll explore the only two kinds of decisions that need to be made in the Dreamcatcher system in order to answer these questions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1-apportioning-fairly-among-contributions">1. Apportioning Fairly Among Contributions<a class="hash-link" href="#1-apportioning-fairly-among-contributions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-tip alert alert--success admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M6.5 0C3.48 0 1 2.19 1 5c0 .92.55 2.25 1 3 1.34 2.25 1.78 2.78 2 4v1h5v-1c.22-1.22.66-1.75 2-4 .45-.75 1-2.08 1-3 0-2.81-2.48-5-5.5-5zm3.64 7.48c-.25.44-.47.8-.67 1.11-.86 1.41-1.25 2.06-1.45 3.23-.02.05-.02.11-.02.17H5c0-.06 0-.13-.02-.17-.2-1.17-.59-1.83-1.45-3.23-.2-.31-.42-.67-.67-1.11C2.44 6.78 2 5.65 2 5c0-2.2 2.02-4 4.5-4 1.22 0 2.36.42 3.22 1.19C10.55 2.94 11 3.94 11 5c0 .66-.44 1.78-.86 2.48zM4 14h5c-.23 1.14-1.3 2-2.5 2s-2.27-.86-2.5-2z"></path></svg></span>Solver vs Solver</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>What is the value of one members solving vs the solving of the other members ?</p></div></div><p>Every outcome in the Dreamcatcher ecosystem is the result of various individual contributions. These could be ideas, funding, software development, QA testing, and more. The question then becomes: how do we apportion attribution fairly among these different contributors?</p><p>To begin with, it's essential to understand that Dreamcatcher operates on the principle of "impact" rather than "effort". That is, the weight of a contribution is measured not by how much time or energy was invested in it, but by its actual impact on the final outcome. </p><p>A robust algorithmic model underpins this decision-making process, assessing the value of each contribution based on a range of parameters. These might include the significance of the contribution to the project, the complexity of the work, and the novelty of the idea, among others. </p><p>Moreover, Dreamcatcher's system is designed to be dynamic and adaptable. As projects evolve and contributions gain or lose relevance, the algorithm adjusts the attribution accorded to each contributor accordingly. This ensures that the attribution system remains fair and accurate, reflecting the ever-changing reality of the project.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2-balancing-attribution-between-funders-solvers-and-dependencies">2. Balancing Attribution Between Funders, Solvers, and Dependencies<a class="hash-link" href="#2-balancing-attribution-between-funders-solvers-and-dependencies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-tip alert alert--success admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M6.5 0C3.48 0 1 2.19 1 5c0 .92.55 2.25 1 3 1.34 2.25 1.78 2.78 2 4v1h5v-1c.22-1.22.66-1.75 2-4 .45-.75 1-2.08 1-3 0-2.81-2.48-5-5.5-5zm3.64 7.48c-.25.44-.47.8-.67 1.11-.86 1.41-1.25 2.06-1.45 3.23-.02.05-.02.11-.02.17H5c0-.06 0-.13-.02-.17-.2-1.17-.59-1.83-1.45-3.23-.2-.31-.42-.67-.67-1.11C2.44 6.78 2 5.65 2 5c0-2.2 2.02-4 4.5-4 1.22 0 2.36.42 3.22 1.19C10.55 2.94 11 3.94 11 5c0 .66-.44 1.78-.86 2.48zM4 14h5c-.23 1.14-1.3 2-2.5 2s-2.27-.86-2.5-2z"></path></svg></span>Funder vs Solver vs Dependencies</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>What is the value of the Funders input vs the Solvers input vs the Dependencies utilized by the Solution ?</p></div></div><p>The second decision concerns the division of attribution between three key player groups in the Dreamcatcher ecosystem: Funders, Solvers, and Dependencies.</p><p>Funders provide the financial resources necessary to bring a project to fruition. Solvers, on the other hand, are the individuals or teams that translate these resources into tangible outputs—be it a piece of software or a brilliant idea. Dependencies represent the pre-existing work or foundational elements upon which new projects are built.</p><p>Each of these groups plays a critical role, and each should receive fair attribution. But what does "fair" mean in this context?</p><p>The key lies in recognizing the unique value brought by each group. Funders provide the means, Solvers provide the skill and creativity, and Dependencies provide the groundwork. Each of these inputs is essential to the project, and the attribution model should reflect that.</p><p>Attribution is therefore divided proportionally based on the value that each group adds to the project. The exact proportions can vary depending on the project, but the principle remains the same: attribution should reflect the true value of each contribution.</p><p>Just as with individual contributors, this process is also dynamic. As the project evolves and the relative importance of funding, solving, and dependencies changes, so too does the distribution of attribution.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a class="hash-link" href="#conclusion" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Dreamcatcher's attribution model is a complex system, designed to fairly and accurately reward all contributors to a project. The two kinds of decisions described here—apportioning among contributions, and balancing between Funders, Solvers, and Dependencies—are the pillars of this system.</p><p>Though the algorithmic models underpinning these decisions are complex, the principle is simple: value is rewarded, impact is recognized, and everyone gets their fair share. That's the Dreamcatcher way.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Packets vs DAOs]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/23/vs-DAOs</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/23/vs-DAOs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Packetisation in the Dreamcatcher vs Decentralised Autonomous Organizations"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image of a dao vs a dreamcatcher as a 3d render" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-dreamcatcher-vs-daos-9b9017034c08e0b25348680eb5819cfc.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Packetised innovation, as exemplified by platforms like Dreamcatcher, offers several advantages over a Decentralised Autonomous Organization (DAO). The model of packetised innovation directly links economic rewards to the value of contributors' input, encouraging everyone to work towards a common goal with the same incentives. It is open to anyone, anywhere, without requiring permission, incentivising high-quality contributions in a barrier-free environment. This process is streamlined by dealing in 'Packets' - unitary pieces of software or knowledge whose quality is verified by a trusted QA and which address a specific need.</p><p>Moreover, the Dreamcatcher platform ensures all members can easily ascertain whether a Packet is 'done' or 'not done,' reducing cost and ambiguity for all involved. The Packets act like immutable equity that cannot be diluted or taken away and are owned by all members who contributed to their creation. They can be traded and can generate revenue streams, ensuring that those who contributed get rewarded. Importantly, these Packets can be re-used in many applications and improved along the way, speeding up development and offsetting costs while providing a passive income stream for original contributors.</p><p>In contrast, while DAOs also operate on principles of decentralisation and transparency, they typically rely on voting mechanisms and workflows for decision-making and control. DAOs, although innovative in their organisational structure, can be hindered by slower decision-making processes due to the requirement of consensus from all members. Additionally, participation in DAOs may be limited to accredited investors only, potentially creating a barrier to entry.</p><p>In summary, packetised innovation allows for more direct, efficient, and inclusive contribution, fostering innovation and value creation while potentially avoiding some of the limitations inherent in DAO structures.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Blockchain the Dreamcatcher]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/23/why-dreamcatcher-blockchain</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/23/why-dreamcatcher-blockchain</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Gen3 Blockchains: Where Contributions Shape Value and Consumers Drive Change"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image of a high tech dreamcatcher formed out of many blockchains that looks like an explosion of paint and rainbows" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-gen3-blockchains-650887602a9a20ab0e1ea6e7a334c8b8.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><ol><li><p><strong>Direct Connection and Micropayments</strong>: Blockchain enables direct, peer-to-peer transactions, allowing Dreamcatcher to connect economic rewards to the value of members' contributions. This technology also facilitates efficient microtransactions, incentivizing every contribution, big or small.</p></li><li><p><strong>Open and Incentivised</strong>: Blockchain provides the infrastructure for an open and global platform, allowing anyone, anywhere to contribute without permission in an open market that transforms ideas into products.</p></li><li><p><strong>Packetised and Quality Guardians</strong>: Dreamcatcher's members deal in 'Packets' - unitary pieces of software or documented knowledge. Blockchain ensures the integrity and ownership of these digital assets. Additionally, it facilitates a reputation system for QA Guardians, who vet these packets.</p></li><li><p><strong>Immutable Attribution and Recombination</strong>: Blockchain ensures that once 'done', Packets act as immutable equity. They can be traded and generate revenue streams, thereby incentivizing their reuse and improvement. Dreamcatcher also utilizes blockchain to automatically track attribution, ensuring a passive income stream for the original contributors.</p></li><li><p><strong>Decentralization and Censorship Resistance</strong>: Dreamcatcher employs a decentralized model of operation. Each application makes its own dedicated set of blockchains for each project, making censorship challenging and ensuring the free expression and development of ideas.</p></li><li><p><strong>Ownership and Privacy</strong>: Dreamcatcher allows each idea to be free-floating, owned by no-one except the blockchain rules, and optionally kept private. Projects, free of any centralized control, can interact with other systems at their discretion, enhancing collaboration and innovation while maintaining individual contribution ownership and privacy.</p></li><li><p><strong>Consumer-Centric Operation</strong>: Inverted apps put their consumers first and coordinate while being fractured into many pieces. They utilize inverted capital allocation mechanisms enabled by Dreamcatcher to perform functions that benefit their consumers, not their controllers.  In contrast to most distributed and decentralized apps where central control is still present in the form of a token or a central registry of intent, inverted apps have no central coordination of intent. Any central tendencies emerge naturally and are apparent when entities communicate, promoting a consumer-focused approach to app operation and development</p></li><li><p><strong>Accessible and Fluid Exchange</strong>: An "inverted" exchange, as conceptualized in Dreamcatcher, allows any participant with commodity electronics to engage, mitigating barriers often found in traditional exchanges. This facilitates peer-to-peer interactions, enabling individuals to find the best prices.</p></li></ol><p>In summary, Dreamcatcher leverages the power of blockchain to create an innovative, consumer-centric ecosystem where value is directly tied to contributions, facilitated by efficient microtransactions. The platform fosters an open, incentivized environment where anyone can contribute, creating 'Packets' of documented knowledge or software that undergo stringent quality checks, thus ensuring their integrity and ownership. These packets, acting as immutable equity, can be traded and reused, generating revenue streams and encouraging continuous improvement. </p><p>Dreamcatcher's decentralized operation, coupled with its commitment to ownership and privacy, ensures a resilient platform resistant to censorship and conducive to free expression. The platform's focus on consumer-centric operation is manifested in its inverted apps, which prioritize consumers and coordinate in a decentralized manner.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dreamcatcher AI]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/22/dreamcatcher-ai</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/22/dreamcatcher-ai</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"The Dawn of Democratised Innovation Attribution"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-05-22-dreamcatcher-ai-97cd54e44c7d581cd8e4cd7fcdc872a0.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In the realm of collaborative innovation, a fundamental question often arises: "Who should receive the fruits of the collective labour?" The answer is often a tangle of complexity, especially when the collaborative process involves numerous contributors over extended periods. Dreamcatcher.land, an open, packetised innovation market, proposes a compelling solution to this problem, serving as a powerful foundation for a more advanced concept: the Dreamcatcher AI. This blog post will explore how Dreamcatcher AI extends the principles of Dreamcatcher.land to build a democratic, data-driven innovation attribution system.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-foundation-dreamcatcherland">The Foundation: Dreamcatcher.land<a class="hash-link" href="#the-foundation-dreamcatcherland" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Dreamcatcher.land is a fascinating innovation machine that directly links economic reward to the value of members' contributions, whether they're involved in funding, buying, or building and selling software. This platform operates on the concept of 'Packets', unitary pieces of software or documented knowledge verified by Quality Guardians, which address identified needs. Once a packet is deemed 'done', it acts like immutable equity attributed to all contributing members. This equity can be traded and generate revenue streams, providing a clear reward for contributions. </p><p>The platform's appeal is further enhanced by its ability to reuse and recombine packets across multiple apps, speeding up development and potentially offsetting costs. If reused packets prove useful, Dreamcatcher tracks attribution automatically, ensuring a passive income stream for original contributors. </p><p>The roles within Dreamcatcher's ecosystem are also worth highlighting. Funders inject capital into projects, with the platform's quality assurance process ensuring that the funded work corresponds to their expectations and that payments are released only for packets that contribute to turning their request into a product. 'Do-ers', the innovators who bring packets to life, can work without arbitrary gatekeepers, earning revenue based on the quality of their work. Buyers, on the other hand, are valued for their needs and rewarded for their product requests, contributing to the innovation process from the demand side.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-evolution-dreamcatcher-ai">The Evolution: Dreamcatcher AI<a class="hash-link" href="#the-evolution-dreamcatcher-ai" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Building upon the Dreamcatcher.land foundation, Dreamcatcher AI represents the next evolutionary step in this democratic approach to innovation. It is an attribution artificial intelligence system built on the data generated from the packet-based innovation protocol of Dreamcatcher.land.</p><p>This AI system is designed to answer the often challenging question of revenue distribution based on individual contributions. It examines the vast dataset of interactions on the platform, learns from these experiences, and applies this knowledge to generate fair, informed attribution decisions. With every interaction from any member, the AI deepens its learning, continuously improving its decision-making capabilities.</p><p>Moreover, Dreamcatcher AI introduces an interesting feedback loop that allows members to signal their dissatisfaction with the AI's output, effectively 'teaching' the AI what they believe the attribution should be. This mechanism enables continuous adjustment of the AI's decision-making processes, embodying the spirit of continuous democracy. Every interaction, every feedback point contributes to this ongoing learning process, refining the system's understanding and making it ever more accurate and fair in its attributions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="democratising-innovation-attribution">Democratising Innovation Attribution<a class="hash-link" href="#democratising-innovation-attribution" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Dreamcatcher AI brings to life a revolutionary concept: a democratized, data-driven system of innovation attribution. It encourages active participation from all members, learning from their interactions and feedback to refine its understanding of fair attribution. This serves not just to improve the AI's decision-making abilities, but also to make the entire process more transparent and equitable.</p><p>Furthermore, the AI system provides a clear mechanism for members to express their views on attribution, ensuring their voices are heard and considered in the decision-making process. The integration of these feedback loops represents a fundamental shift in how innovation ecosystems can operate, moving from a static, hierarchical structure to a dynamic, democratised system.</p><p>To conclude, Dreamcatcher AI stands at the forefront of a new era of innovation, where data-driven decisions and democratic processes combine to deliver fair and transparent attribution. As members interact with the system, they are not just passive participants but active contributors to the AI's learning. Every interaction, every piece of feedback, is a step towards refining the system and making it more reflective of the collective will of the members. This continuous democratic process holds immense potential for the future of collaborative innovation, painting a promising picture of what's to come. </p><p>Through the combined power of Dreamcatcher.land's packet-based innovation protocol and Dreamcatcher AI's learning and feedback mechanism, we are witnessing a paradigm shift in how we approach innovation. This harmonious blend of technology and democracy brings us closer to a future where every contributor is adequately recognised and rewarded, catalysing a more inclusive and sustainable innovation ecosystem.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Network is the Innovator]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2023/05/22/network-is-the-innovator</link>
            <guid>/2023/05/22/network-is-the-innovator</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Exploring Innovation Networks: Analogies from Network Communications"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="bing: an image depicting the network as the innovator, with the network looking like a dreamcatcher, and the innovator represented by cogs and lightbulbs" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-network-innovator-1313ffd1ed8bcc93b02b3f71964c0995.jpeg" width="1024" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Our interconnected world often presents opportunities to draw parallels between seemingly disparate fields. One such perspective can be gained by comparing full-time employees, contractors, and the Dreamcatcher packet model in the context of the evolution of innovation networks, with dedicated lines, circuit-switched networks, and packet-switched networks, in the context of the evolution of the internet.</p><p>For those unfamiliar, consider full-time employees as dedicated lines in a network. Just as dedicated lines provide a fixed, uninterrupted path for data transmission between two points, full-time employees are focused, consistent contributors to a single organization. This arrangement ensures stability, but it may lack flexibility.</p><p>On the other hand, contractors can be likened to circuit-switched networks. Much like how circuit-switching establishes a temporary path for data transmission, contractors provide services on an as-needed basis, offering greater flexibility but possibly less consistency compared to full-time employees.</p><p>Bringing the Dreamcatcher platform into the mix, it can be compared to packet-switched networks. The packet-switching method involves grouping data into packets that are independently routed to their destination, where they are reassembled. Similarly, the Dreamcatcher platform allows for the decentralization and independent progress of ideas or innovations, which can then be pieced together to create comprehensive solutions.</p><p>However, the packet-switched approach, or in our analogy, the Dreamcatcher Network, isn't without its challenges:</p><ol><li>Discontinuity: Just as packets may arrive at the destination out of order, ideas within a Dreamcatcher network can be disjointed or lack cohesion.</li><li>Conversions: Much like data packets need to be formatted and checked for errors before transmission, innovations on the Dreamcatcher platform often require formalization and validation before they can be implemented.</li></ol><p>Despite these challenges, the benefits of the Dreamcatcher approach to innovation are notable. By embracing the inherent discontinuity and conversion processes, we can create an innovation network that is dynamic, resilient, and adaptive.</p><p>In this model, the network itself becomes the innovator. It's not about any single entity or full-time employee driving change, but rather the collective effort of the network, with each node (where a node is a Dreamcatcher participant) contributing to the overall innovation.</p><p>We can visualize the innovation process as a series of information circuits, each with its unique challenges and opportunities. These circuits may have unreliable operation, delays, lost packets (unrealized ideas), and varying costs. </p><p>However, just as in a packet-switched network, the ability to break down a large packet (or idea) into smaller pieces, transport them via alternate routes, and reassemble them at the destination can prove to be highly effective. This approach allows for parallel processing, resilience in the face of obstacles, and the integration of diverse perspectives.</p><p>In conclusion, viewing innovation through the lens of packet-switching networks - or in our case, the Dreamcatcher network - opens up exciting possibilities for the way we conceptualize, manage, and execute innovation. By embracing the network as the innovator, we can build a more resilient, adaptive, and efficient innovation ecosystem.</p><p><em>Reference:</em> <a href="https://www.livinginternet.com/i/iw_packet_inv.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Packet Switching History</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[app-complexity]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2022/05/23/app-complexity</link>
            <guid>/2022/05/23/app-complexity</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2023-05-23-app-complexity-1a4658ef4918bfdcca6e95bebbd6ae4a.png" width="1338" height="1162" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Background for The Pool Process]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2022/05/22/why-separate-problems-and-ideas</link>
            <guid>/2022/05/22/why-separate-problems-and-ideas</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Target]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>IN DRAFT</h1><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="target">Target<a class="hash-link" href="#target" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://github.com/dreamcatcher-tech/dreamcatcher-tech.github.io/blob/master/website/nfas/Ideas/I11.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I11 Request-Idea</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="inherits">Inherits<a class="hash-link" href="#inherits" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dependencies">Dependencies<a class="hash-link" href="#dependencies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-ask-for-requests-and-ideas-to-be-divided">Why ask for Requests and Ideas to be divided?<a class="hash-link" href="#why-ask-for-requests-and-ideas-to-be-divided" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>It's not a vague vs precise thing. It's headmark vs compass bearing thing.</p><p>The general rule is that you should always know what your '1-up' is trying to do, regardless is what he's telling you to do. It's recognising that centralised command and control is inferior to decentralised command and control, but by decentralising, you could give misfires. You need to let the guys know not only what you think they need to do, but why you've asked them to do it.</p><p>So the strategic intent is the high level "Start with why". That's needed because it's not possible to write the tactical intent (the compass bearing) in sufficient detail to avoid fuck ups by itself, you need to give a headmark. But it's not enough to just state why you're trying to do something (the headmark), without giving some guidance.</p><p>The Ratcatchers and Regulators thing comes from Admiral Beatty and Admiral Jellicoe in WW1. Beatty was the ratcatcher, and didn't plan ahead at all well, and gave full reign to the captains under his command. Didn't go well, as they each had a different idea of what the overall objective was, and so perfectly executed their own commands, just in different directions. Jellicoe was the Regulator, and literally had a huge book of rules which all the captains under his command had to follow, and so was exceptionally brittle as soon as the hun came over the horizon.</p><p>The middle ground is the way. Don't over specify, don't leave people in doubt of what the whole point of the thing is.</p><p>So it's fundamentally different from nested Requests, in that strategy is about why, then there's a phase change to tactical which is about how, what, where etc.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blockchain Without Currency]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2022/05/14/blockchain-without-currency</link>
            <guid>/2022/05/14/blockchain-without-currency</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/blockchain-without-currency-354cf8c79bb19bcf7236038dd19db2f0.jpg" width="2048" height="1365" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The destiny of blockchain is to model the entire world. What point then is any instrinsic currency ?</p><p>Object oriented programming is the dominant form of computer modelling.</p><p>Our purpose is to facilitate trade between all currencies and all objects, predominantly labour, technology, customers, and assets.</p><p>With enough granularity and autonomous agents, we can get back to barter.</p><p>When we first started towards the Dreamcatcher, we wanted software defined companies, to cure the ailments we had in our current publicly listed companies. Now we're saying that each object comes with a software defined company attached via API.</p><p>Why aren't software defined companies popular ? What are manually operated companies the favourite ? Is there some relationship between the granularity of a thing before it becomes programmable ?</p><p>Points</p><ol><li>Future of all currencies is to be replaced with barter</li><li>Any crypto currency is arbitrary anyway</li><li>Object models allow direct trading of the item</li><li>We can model any currency, with provenance, and fractionalize it to nano portions</li><li>miners can earn whatever currency they wish</li><li>liquid exchanges let you swap for any other currency</li><li>There is no currency since the value we are creating is captured in the NFTs that make up the system</li></ol><p>Given that we built this whole thing on non-fungibility and modelling of the real world, it makes no sense to have a currency of our own.
Any arbitrary fungible unit of value that has no internal control mechanism will periodically crash.
With no regulation, this cycle is accelerated, as the system can be used as a 'bigger fool' scheme, but is harder to squash due to its distributed nature, with a multitude of bad actors having no coordination except the same pattern of ill intent.</p><p>Systems that launch with a 'shares' like nature, such as ICOs and other "Initial <!-- -->*<!-- -->" offerings bake in their demise from inception by setting the exectations and incentives of multiple powerful actors in the system.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Innovation Information Gradients]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2021/12/19/information-gradients</link>
            <guid>/2021/12/19/information-gradients</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The question was: "When asked "what does the Dreamcatcher do ?" how can we include this graph at the heart of what it does ? "oh it makes things fairer" isn't very precise. Showing the wage theft gap as the addressable market for the Dreamcatcher says it has a lot of potential, in provable numbers, I think ?"</p><p>I think we're missing the main point if we talk about removing power from Capital. We're not leading a revolution - we're tuning an old, large engine that could do so much better... But we need to convince Capital and Labour to make it work. We can't do that by being anti-capital.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/Real_GDP_Real_Wages_and_Trade_Policies_in_the_U.S._1947_2014-dc0fc03b9ec821ed0c14048af24b4769.png" width="861" height="691" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Bear with me now, as half an eye to turning this into a blog-piece, and typing this on a phone...
Previously we had two main economic models:</p><p>Labour dominant: Communism at it's core was to remove influence from capital and rent seekers towards Labour. To do that, it was necessary to centralise as there was no pracical alternative. Guessing I don't need to say why centralisation is bad, other than summarising: few brains = bad; many brains = good.</p><p>Capital dominant: Capitalism aimed to decentralise, but failed because of network effects. The more Capital produced, the more than can be produced, and so there's (all else being equal), a exponential effect that accumulates Capital over time. So you inevitably end up with small and reducing group of Capital holders. Not helpful. Again, few brains = bad; many brains = good.</p><p>[Sidenote - this distinction between Capital and Labour is outdated, but going to use it as a traditional framework below. By example, the four of us are working together now. Who's Capital and who's Labour? Say if we hire a guy at half pay, and half Attribution? Who's Capital and who's Labour then? The point is the differentiation is in reality blurred - there just hasn't been a practical way to recognise that until now.]<!-- -->
So what we're proposing is a third way.</p><p>Many brains &lt;-&gt; Many brains = genius.</p><p>NB, no one is losing out here. Both Capital and Labour are improving efficiency. Laying to one side arguments that benefit is relative to your immediate neighbours which you compare yourself with, improving efficiency has got to be a good thing...
AXIOM - Innovation is a good, as of and by itself. Making Innovation more efficient is therefore necessarily good.
So to test this, here's a thought experiment. Two people, one is the Capital guy, the other the Labour guy.</p><p>It's important to note that there is a symetry there. The Capital guy can fire the Labour guy, and the Labour guy can fire the Capital guy (by resigning). But there's an asymetry of information - the information gradient.</p><p>Have talked about this Information Gradient a bit, but this is more important than it may seem. These two don't live in the same world. Capital guy knows about capital; Labour guy knows how to build stuff to make a ROI. Capital guy knows very little about Labour guy's world; Labour guy knows little about Capital guy's world. So we're now approaching a zero-sum game. Each will be looking out for themselves (of course) - even though it would be to the benefit of both if the Project succeeds.
Therefore:
AXIOM - Wherever that's an Information Gradient, there's an inefficient market.
To dig in to the world as seen by each of the players:</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="capital-guy">Capital Guy<a class="hash-link" href="#capital-guy" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Capital guy is trying to increase his pile by using it to build Stuff, sell Stuff, and make Return on Capital Employed. But he doesn't have the skills, so he needs to give it to some CEO, who will then go off and hire a bunch of people to execute on an idea. To find the CEO he's probably having to look through his local network to N levels of separation, depending on his patience. In my experience, N=2, which is pants.</p><p>He then has to offload his own aim of building his pile to this CEO guy, who then goes out to look for talent to build the idea. That's a fraught process, and I'd argue close to being random selection, based on some filter. So the Capital guy ends up worrying about his Contribution being spanked on marketing socks (Tom, Ben, you get the reference), "Tribe Two" consultants out to gouge a day-rate (Tom, yup, you'll also get the reference), and because of the Information Gradient, Capital Guy has no idea whether his pile will increase or disappear.</p><p>Worth thinking about that for a moment. Capital guy has close to zero control about whether his Contribution will provide a Return, beyond, well, you know, shouting, firing people, closing the company etc.</p><p>The result is that start-up investment is seen as ludicrously risky, and so the risk multiplier means that the Capital guy would be an idiot to not grab as large a percentage of the pie as possible, even before the pie is ready to go in the oven.</p><p>In addition, at the early stages, Capital guy has the Information Gradient in his favour. Two guys in a garage vs Round-A $3m...</p><p>I do have a lot of sympathy for the Capital guy though. Being out of control sucks. Capital guys doesn't have real control, beyond raising, hiring, firing and folding. So small number of Big Hammers...</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="labour-guy">Labour Guy<a class="hash-link" href="#labour-guy" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>OK, so other side of the coin, the Labour Guy. Labour Guy has more direct control over what's produced, but they have perverse incentives (cf Adam Smith). You could work hard on what the Capital guy wants you to do, but you're also interested in increasing your pile. How to do that? A smart Labour guy will be trading off working full tilt on the Project, setting up their own Project, maybe gouging for salary while the going is good.</p><p>But again the Information Gradient kicks in. Capital guy has identified that there's a large risk, and so will be holding as much of the pie as possible for as long as possible. Labour guy can bake that pie, but won't go full tilt if he's not going to get any. It's a zero-sum game.</p><p>Again, Information Gradient = inefficient market.</p><p>So we get the weirdness of two groups, who if they cooperated with each other could build The Thing, expecting that it's a zero sum game and, using the tools each have to hand, trying to maximise their own return not the important thing, which is to see whether That Thing is useful in the market.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dreamcatcher">Dreamcatcher<a class="hash-link" href="#dreamcatcher" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>AXIOM: Dreamcatcher intends to reduce and ultimately remove the inefficiencies we see now in Innovation.
From the Capital guy's point of view, the ideal situation is that the Labour guy is working full tilt on the Project. Ie, there's zero Information Gradient between what the Capital guy wants and what the Labour guy wants.</p><p>From the Labour guy's point of view, the ideal situation is that the Capital guy will give him his full worth of the effort he puts in. Ie, there's zero Information Gradient between what the Capital guy wants and what the Labour guy wants.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/Labor_capital_balance-981f029551c689692d5a5f8443b54bd5.jpg" width="1485" height="839" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>So there's a potential here that there is no information gradient, and that both groups have exactly the same incentives
And that's my point. Dreamcatcher isn't anti-capital, anti-rent-seakers (although I hate rent-seekers). It is about working towards making Innovation maximally efficient, which isn't a zero-sum game. If it works, everyone benefits...
@everyone Feel passionately about this. Know we have a lot going back and forth, but would love it if one of you guys would kick the shit out of what I've said above. Right now, for me, that reduction in inefficiency of innovation is everything, and we need to lead with that not being a zero-sum game...</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inverted Applications]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2021/03/18/inverted-applications</link>
            <guid>/2021/03/18/inverted-applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/inverted_applications-7dfbef9e72c11ed17714654dadb6c345.jpg" width="800" height="350" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Distributed apps at best can have tamper detection.</p><p>Decentralized apps at best can have censor resistance.</p><p>Consider then a github clone with a central token. Once roughly 51% of all the governance tokens have been controlled, which could be done by censoring maybe three or four people if not distributed well, then the entire app is at the will of the censor. Worse, perhaps the underlying blockchain is overthrown somehow - then the github token goes down as collateral (excuse the pun) damage. The problem is confounded by the requirement that surviving blockchain operators need to communicate with each other, as forking is considered a system failure. This repeated communication makes them easy targets. Yes, the system could start again as soon as the first copy re-appears and starts operating, but during that window the censor is in control - supression is the norm.</p><p>An inverted version of github makes its own dedicated set of blockchains for each git repo that anyone wishes to host. These apps might communicate with each other, and might even trade using some currency selections. They might share block producers, they might not.</p><p>To take down an inverted app requires finding all the blockhosts and all the key owners of all the github repos that every get created using this means of operation. The problem is far thornier than the other classes of apps. We believe this is censorship proof operation - if a censor can find every actor who is running a copy of the software. Whole subsegments of user can go offnet, and run local only. You can only supress what you can detect, and so this is the worst possible scenario of any censorship effort - we should strive for this, and not accept inferior systems that offer anything less that censorship proof apps for everyday users.</p><p>Email is an example of a sort of inverted app. It has massive distribution, it is not centrally controlled. The central control however, is exerted by the DNS namespace, and the IP allocation tables of the internet. but it has many of the characteristics, and its wild spread indicates the scale for these types of apps. It could be that email is the simplest form of such a thing, as it really just does transmission and receiving. More complex and more useful interactions such as long form stateful collaborations have yet to see such an exlosion, but git offers a glimpse of what that could be like. If only git came with its own independent version of github wrapped around every repo that was created. Its components lack the resilience and internal integrity necessary to travel thru many inverted instances unaltered.</p><p>The first inverted app is the dreamcatcher. Each idea is free floating, owned by its creator and optionally private. Then projects are created - themselves a form of idea - to capture these ideas, seek missing ideas, and refine them into something usable. Each project is entirely sovereign to itself, optionally run by whomever has compute capacity to do so. It is completely free of any centralized token control, system control, or even version control. It can, at the freewill of its owners, communicate with other organisms such as itself, or with other external systems such as email.</p><p>The spreading of a codebase creates a desire for future improvements to that program. This is primarily how we get paid, and the service we are offering - future improvements quickly, of quality. The more people get copies of our software, the more pressure is created.</p><p>The power of enduring social pressure. The emergent will of a thousand whispers.</p><p>Inverted apps put their consumer first, and coordinate while being fractured into many pieces. inverted apps harness the inverted capital allocation mechanisms enabled by dreamcatchers to perform functions in line with the benefit of their consumers, not their controllers. Distributed apps spread the operation of an application across multiple physical machines with control held by a central entity. Almost all cloud applications that hope to offer any kind of reliability operate in this way. Decentralized apps are distributed apps that spread the central control amongst many entities, often dynamically. Whilst the control may be spread around, the central control is still fiercely present, usually in the form of a token as a central registry of intent. Inverted apps are the opposite of these forms, in that there is no central coordination of intent, but rather any central tendencies emerges, without force or registration, and are apparent when entities communicate. For example, the collection of all bitcoin chain forks is a crude form of inverted app - the forks do not communicate well with each other, but their central token registries are at least partially split from each other to serve the needs of their respective user groups, and sometimes they coordinate via exchanges where overall, the utility of cryptocurrencies of this class is enhanced. Inverted apps can easily wrap controlled apps, but controlled apps are incapable of wrapping inverted. Inverted can wrap inverted. Inverted can emulate controlled where needed. Almost all blockchains could currently be classed as perverted apps - proporting to offer freedom, but really having no more structure than a public company with central product and distributed public shareholdings. These operations have no future.</p><p>an inverted exchange is different to an exchange on a blockchain. True inversion means that any partipant can come and go if the possess commodity electronics. Ethereum for example you need to have ETH, then you need assets on the chain - the list of barriers goes on and on. An inverted exchange would let people peer with one another and find the best prices. Yes there would appear aggregators, but these would be assistants, and easily replaced at any time they stop being useful.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="No SaaS" src="/assets/images/no-more-software-7f0bf35734eb2392d46e0393f283fd37.png" width="277" height="182" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>A new software delivery model for SaaS is <a href="https://goteleport.com/blog/open-core-vs-saas-intro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">emerging</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>infosec</category>
            <category>privacy</category>
            <category>tor</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Value of Structured Dissent]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2021/02/22/Structured-Dissent</link>
            <guid>/2021/02/22/Structured-Dissent</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Dreamcatcher aims to provide a mechanism for alternate views on all aspects of a Project not only to co-exist, but to combine to improve that project and all Forks of that project.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dreamcatcher aims to provide a mechanism for alternate views on all aspects of a Project not only to co-exist, but to combine to improve that project and all Forks of that project.</p><p>This stems from the belief that it’s hard to see individually what particular opinions are correct ahead of time, and that the more outlandish opinions may often be the most valuable. It also stems from the belief that in gathering many opinions, de-duplicating and combining them to become more precise, and by combining the judgement of many people in deciding their worth, we’re maximising the chance of making the right decisions.</p><p>This approach is across the board. It applies just as much to how a Project is governed, how it’s funds are spent as it does to what work should be undertaken and whether it’s complete.</p><p>That is, the method of consideration needs in itself to be open to opinion and consideration.</p><p>This is important because, generally, the closer you are to the work, the clearer your thoughts on the appropriateness of that work. Likewise, the closer you are to the overall goals, the clearer your thoughts are on those. The DC needs to capture both, filter and apply wide knowledge on assessing them.</p><p>We want to be able to capture the fringe ideas because that's where the big gains come from. We also simultaneously want to manage a wealth of fringe ideas without being paralysesed when those ideas are incompatible with each other.</p><p>The Principles are:</p><ol><li>Give us everything. It should be free and easily done to raise any level of idea, from all levels of the project from the work being done to how the project is being run to the Wishes the project is pursuing.</li><li>Then to be sensitive enough to detect which ideas are valuable, and to amplify and act on those quickly. We do this through de-duplication and merging to sort out the noise, and amplification of those views that stand the test of peer-review scrutiny.</li><li>And where agreement can’t be found, give an easy route to Fork the Project, explore both stances to see which one is actually the better, and allow a merge back in preserving the history of both.</li></ol><p>By doing this, the speed of the project to react to new circumstances or new knowledge is maximised, way beyond any traditional project
structure.</p><p>Dreamcatcher is the home for all of those lone-wolf, smart guys that have so much untapped value, but which are drowned in the rigid structures that are currently used to produce stuff.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inverted Cloud]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2021/02/22/inverted-cloud</link>
            <guid>/2021/02/22/inverted-cloud</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/cloud-at-home-7ab31e4d88e01ee84437bca0db1d678b.jpg" width="1600" height="576" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>"AMD Silicon" covers wide range too:</p><ol><li>circuit designers</li><li>silicon fab</li><li>supply chain</li></ol><p>Our applications must be easily portable to this mode of operation</p><p>Need to move to open silicon, with trusted fabs</p><p>If cloud@home then the workload is rapidly relocatable, and so the customer may choose to run some base load on prem, have other load on cloud@home, and sell their spare capacity on cloud@home</p><p>cloud@home makes use of idle resources, and shares yours out too. you can have enough resiliency for standalone operation in a disaster, but can rent this capacity out when not in use</p><p>Show diagram of comparitive trust chains, latency, cost, fault tolerance of cloud configurations</p><p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2020/07/14/google_amd_secure_vm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.theregister.com/2020/07/14/google_amd_secure_vm/</a>
So your chain of trust can now be as short as "AMD silicon", Which paves the way for cloud at home type scenarios where renting off a home supplier has the same security guarantees as renting off a cloud supplier</p><p>event driven workloads designed for distributed storage - so the workloads would have to be designed specifically for cloud@home unless its just small little apps</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambient Attribution]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2020/12/20/ambient-attribution</link>
            <guid>/2020/12/20/ambient-attribution</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[k]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Mirror mirror, on the wall, who is the fairest of them all?"</em></p><p>Contents</p><ol><li>Example project funding of Interblock</li><li>Example project funding of DOS</li></ol><p>Software companies make up trillions of dollars on the stockmarket, but the best
quality software is actually free - how can we connect these two extremes to
something more sustainable, and how can we get more software, of a higher
quality, faster, and cost lest money ?</p><p>The utopian model of knowledge work is that all individuals permissionlessly contribute to whatever they are able, in whatever form they can, and can build on all prior contributions from anyone else, while receiving fair recompense based on the value they provided whenever their work is used and reused, all with zero overhead. This utopia is focused on providing pure utility to consumers, and enabling pure contribution from producers. This environment would be ideal Ambient Attribution.</p><p>To implement such perfection in our current reality needs compromise and ingenuity. A pragmatic form of Ambient Attribution as presented here has mechanisms to handle corruption, fairness discovery, attack mitigation (eg: lawsuits and corporation pressures), dishonesty, disputes, transaction costs, and management overheads, all while avoiding the perils of central system control. Whilst the perfected version may be some decades away technologically, we see within the rise of blockchains, the basic components required to implement a first iteration. This is what we set out to embody within the Dreamcatcher.</p><p>Based on two forces:</p><ol><li>fair credit due everywhere</li><li>zero friction for reuse</li></ol><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Iron Triangle of Time vs Cost vs Quality" src="/assets/images/good-fast-cheap-02cc4d4c2aa49b62bd30491906c625f3.jpg" width="1926" height="1742" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>These qualities change the bigger the pool gets <!-- -->[graphic of pool size vs ideal
match]<!-- --> Biggest pool is the lowest friction quality largely depends on the people
you have available. let us assume their is an optimal piece of work, at an
optimal price. the more people can do the work the better. less friction, zero
friction company. zero liability, zero friction, never credit. credit being
given by the worker, acting as a bank. <!-- -->[graph showing decreasing overall cost]</p><p><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/sweat-equity-5d5230e4b10d12993269d4f2253ddc85.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/blog/2020-12-20-assets/sweat-equity.jpg" height="480" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><p>decreasing activation cost longer it survives, the better the quality a good
programmer on their day public scrutiny, even if perceived can be called to
account years after your coding</p><p>how much reward is fair ? surmise there is a single fair answer. self witness,
shared witness, unto others as they unto you, wisdom of crowds image should be
the same looking back, no different. how they see you should be same as how you
see them. this is shared vision - aka reality. fairness is something that looks
the same from all sides</p><p>What is fair payment ? Depend on each situation. Depends on the utility gained.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="example-funding-interblock">Example: Funding Interblock<a class="hash-link" href="#example-funding-interblock" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>What is the prize ?</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-the-product-">What is the product ?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-is-the-product-" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Equity stake in the upside. Consumers of the product are politly asked for fair
payment</p><p>Types of input:</p><ol><li>Direct funds used by project command</li><li>Code contribution</li><li>Direct funded code contribution</li><li>Early customer</li></ol><p>We hope these models of labour, if successful, can have equivalents in the
physical product world.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="restrictions-on-investment">Restrictions on investment<a class="hash-link" href="#restrictions-on-investment" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Any projects that we endorse must follow the following rules, which are
automated:</p><ol><li>Investors must prove they know what the project is about</li><li>Investors must be able to afford to lose their investment</li><li>Projects must have an earnest goal</li></ol><p>We are unable to register many of our projects with the SEC due to our
requirements to stay anonymous. However we support the spirit of the SEC
regulations, and we aim to exceed their intention.</p><p>To invest in a software project, you must have made a code commit of more than x
weighted value, which signals that you know what the project is about, and you
have contributed enough to be part of the enterprise - a worker, as it were -
relying on the efforts of others and yourself to show return.</p><p>Work cannot be faked, copied, or otherwise, and it makes no difference to its
utility if it was done by a machine, a person, or a small dog. It doesn't matter
if it was done in a virtual machine, bare metal, at gunpoint, or of freewill -
it is like gold - it can be tested for purity, and not counterfeited, unlike
fiat, and unlike promises, which is what fiat is.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>infosec</category>
            <category>privacy</category>
            <category>tor</category>
            <category>blockchain</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side Effect IO]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2020/10/26/side-effects</link>
            <guid>/2020/10/26/side-effects</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"Mixing the pure with the impure, without making everything impure"</em></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mixing-droplet-cc99a7cf93ede713e25b9f9bd1091783.jpg" width="4856" height="3380" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The work I have been doing lately could largely be described as side effect management. This is the means by which to introduce external data into the blockchain based system, in a way that does not corrupt the key blockchain property of reproducibility. That is to say, being able to rerun blocks thru different computers and verify that the same answer came out. Side effects are any external event - something that cannot be reproduced - a simple example is receiving an email. The converse is required too - being able to use the pure, clean, secure blockchain based calculations to trigger unreproducible external events. A simple example of this is sending an email.</p><p>So the work is about making something unrepeatable become something repeatable in a clean way, and to a lesser extent making something repeatable trigger unrepeatable events.</p><p>However during the work I was doing to send internet packets between Amazon and the browser the amount of code I was writing that was not blockchain related started to increase. The problem with this is that it is not reusing the code that is used for the blockchains, and so requires extra work to build and maintain, while losing the very helpful traceability properties that blockchain based calculations afford. Traceability becomes especially useful when the software is executing on remote servers.</p><p>This was the trigger for the work, but it is work that would have been required later anyway.</p><p>I have managed to get the underlying system of side effects working in prototype form, and starting from this morning I will be applying that to the internet transport ability. I am pleased with how the system is performing, and it meets my goals of being clean and simple and easy to fault find. An example of why the fault finding aspect is useful is that if you call me and say that at roughly 10am something weird happened in the app and you can't seem to make it happen again, we would be able to see the actual interactions the application made and very quickly be able to reproduce the problem, making fixing it much faster, and giving you reassurance that we did actually know what is going on, rather than having to ask you to keep an eye out for it happening again because we can't notice anything amiss.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zero Liability Companies]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2020/09/24/zero-liability-co</link>
            <guid>/2020/09/24/zero-liability-co</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When was it first invented]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dragon-ab1419ce479b7acd7fc9cf30df9dd6cc.jpg" width="1500" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>When was it first invented</p><p>But the only truly zero liability company is a fully anonymous one.</p><p>Building customer trust</p><p>The only way to protect the privacy of your customers is to ensure they remain anoymous.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Current Labour Flows" src="/assets/images/economy-d606caca4ff3bcb7b2fd4f9a960bd520.png" width="882" height="662" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Switching cost for customers is high, so they will tolerate erosion of value before switching. Also company 1 and the livelihoods of all their staff are destroyed by a mass switch, when perhaps the majority of the company did good work. Then the process repeats again for company 2.</p><p>We propose a means by which there is really only one company, and the members cooperate at whim, and the consumers pay down whichever paths suit them best.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="outsourcing-your-identity-management-requirements">Outsourcing your identity management requirements.<a class="hash-link" href="#outsourcing-your-identity-management-requirements" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>In such an ecosystem, the dangerous job of correlating identities need only be managed by a handful of services.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="exceeding-quality-of-registered-companies">Exceeding quality of registered companies<a class="hash-link" href="#exceeding-quality-of-registered-companies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Companies do bad things all the time. Clearly being registered is no guarantee of good behaviour. With zero liability, the responsibily shifts onto the community to maintain opinion... This correlates with a shift in social mob justice of suspected bad actors.</p><p>Complete anonymity and business models that still work (hopefully!) even tho buy side and sell side do not know who each other are.</p><p>Making a functioning revenue stream when there is no force available - how to make money from open source software.</p><p>Transparency of companies is somewhat like how on a unix system, the operating system is largely readable by all users, but only writable by a trusted few. It helps the users to know whats going on.</p><p>We only care about the work generated. Work is hard, and full of thorns as the level of detail increases. Being zero liability and anonymous frees people to focus solely on the work, and frees consumers to look only at the value of that work to them, independent of any other forces that can alter perception away from cold purity of value. It is then up to the producer to choose to declare what they have done - this is optional, whereas under the current systems it is required, and criminally punished.</p><p>Moreover, we have implemented ways in which people can partially declare properties about themselves and their work rather than a full destruction of privacy. For example you can declare yourself a tax resident of x country for the projects you contributed there, and you can pay tax to that country, but you need not assosciate your name with it.</p><p>The bringers of novel knowledge are often unwelcomed, some violently so (references). For this reason, the Dreamcatcher network is designed such that any contributors of work or funds are free to stay anonymous, and at their wish only reveal as much as they wish. They can also release graduated information rather than all or nothing. Indeed consumers within the network also can operate this way, and share any portion of their consumption data on the network</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="operating-activities">Operating Activities<a class="hash-link" href="#operating-activities" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Real life promotion (conferences, videos, friends)</li><li>Online Promotion (forums, emails, blogs)</li><li>Code commits</li><li>Issue posting</li><li>TESTING Amazon deployments using serverless.com tooling</li><li>PRODUCTION Amazon deployments using serverless.com tooling</li></ol><p>the concept of the zero liability company only the code matters</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Race for Mechanized Innovation]]></title>
            <link>https://dreamcatcher.land/blog/2019/05/22/race-for-mechanized-invention</link>
            <guid>/2019/05/22/race-for-mechanized-invention</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Why the panic to create an invention machine ? One of the founders of Dreamcatcher Inc describes the burden carried by all those who know how to let the genie out of the bottle, and the consequences of delayed release.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why the panic to create an invention machine ? One of the founders of Dreamcatcher Inc describes the burden carried by all those who know how to let the genie out of the bottle, and the consequences of delayed release.</p><p>5/22/19, 14:13 - 🦄: What about all the people dying around the world because of cures not yet invented? Is it our fault, if it makes a cure, and say 10 people died in the previous 3 months, and we're like "remember that three months we fucked around for?"</p><p>5/22/19, 14:15 - ☢️: Shit that’s a good point.</p><p>5/22/19, 14:15 - ☢️: Zero tolerance of delay.</p><p>5/22/19, 14:20 - 🦄: Fuck man. Is that an unreasonable burden to put on us?</p><p>5/22/19, 14:20 - ☢️: Erm, no...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:21 - ☢️: Unless you fancy quitting 🤣</p><p>5/22/19, 14:21 - 🦄: Just cuz we know what it is, now it's our burden to make it?</p><p>5/22/19, 14:21 - ☢️: Yes, precisely</p><p>5/22/19, 14:23 - ☢️: So cast your mind forward until you’re 80 years old. Starting to lose it but not yet. Pissing yourself occasionally. Multiple things fucking up your body. Guys born 30 years, 40 years after you now calling the shots. Then ask what you want to do with the time between then and now. How to get those guys harnessing all of those kick-ass concepts that are lost to the wind...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:24 - ☢️: Or leave it to them and hope someone else comes up with an Invention Machine...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:24 - ☢️: Never know, maybe someone will</p><p>5/22/19, 14:24 - ☢️: My guess is they won’t</p><p>5/22/19, 14:25 - ☢️: Because they’ll still be stuck by the stuff we’re trying to unstick</p><p>5/22/19, 14:26 - ☢️: So what, we have maybe 40 years useful left. 8800 days of work. About 70,000 hours</p><p>5/22/19, 14:27 - ☢️: And there goes another 4 from the time we called <!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- --> this morning</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="tick tock mf" src="/assets/images/tick-tock-debate-me-efea8a01f04e1906203bc4b7a3f5c3b3.gif" width="498" height="325" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>5/22/19, 14:27 - ☢️: Tick tock motherfucker…</p><p>5/22/19, 14:28 - ☢️: Then game over</p><p>5/22/19, 14:28 - ☢️: So, given all that. How long should we fuck around with the likes of <!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- -->?</p><p>5/22/19, 14:28 - ☢️: A year so far. Or about 2000 of those hours...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:29 - ☢️: It’s taken about 35,000 hours just to get to this point...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:29 - ☢️: One third gone</p><p>5/22/19, 14:30 - ☢️: Two thirds left</p><p>5/22/19, 14:32 - ☢️: “Despite this success, more than 3 million people die from vaccine-preventable diseases each year. Approximately 1.5 million of these deaths are in children less than 5 years old”</p><p>5/22/19, 14:33 - ☢️: So say there’s an invention the Invention Machine will find that stops 0.1% of that.</p><p>5/22/19, 14:34 - ☢️: Three months delay isn’t 10 people. It’s 750...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:35 - ☢️: And fucking around with <!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- -->*<!-- --> is 3000...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:36 - ☢️: There’s huge value in getting something done by painting a vision. We can’t do this all the way just the two of us, but we can define the story others rally around</p><p>5/22/19, 14:38 - ☢️: “Just cuz we know what it is, now it's our burden to make it?” Yes, it is. Bring it on!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="3000 people" src="/assets/images/3000-people-fdcd6555a44cab3fc9b3f347b2c63a90.png" width="512" height="260" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>This is what 3000 people look like...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:41 - ☢️: Bear in mind you’re talking to the guy who thought he was about to kill 45,000 in 30 days at a 95% assurance of 70% probability in order to save 60,000,000...</p><p>5/22/19, 14:45 - ☢️: So, sense of urgency? Hell yes</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>